JIYOUNG LEE

↑ https://github.com/jiyounglee-0523 ♦ https://jiyounglee-0523.github.io
ijyounglee0523@kaist.ac.kr

RESEARCH INTEREST

MAIN INTEREST: Evaluate AI models to ensure they align with human values and perception **KEYWORDS**: benchmarks, AI-human alignment, safety, social ethics

My research focuses on assessing AI models before deployment to ensure they align with human values and perception across multiple dimensions, including uncertainty, social ethics, and linguistic diversity. I primarily investigate whether (1) AI models exhibit robustness to human variations, such as dialects, and (2) they can recognize and interpret the world in a manner similar to humans.

Through my work in constructing benchmarks, I have extensive experience in conducting human surveys involving over 6,000 participants, actively collaboration with experts from different fields, and applying statistical knowledge to build robust datasets.

EDUCATION

Ph.D in Artifical Intelligence

Sep 2022 - Present

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), Daejeon, South Korea

Advisor: Prof. Edward Choi

M.Sc. in Artifical Intelligence

Sep 2020 - Aug 2022

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST), Daejeon, South Korea

Advisor: Prof. Edward Choi

B.Sc. in Statistics

March 2016 - Aug 2020

Sookmyung Women's University, Seoul, South Korea

GPA: 4.08 / 4.3 (Ranked 1st in the Department of Statistics)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Machine Translation Research Intern

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

Naver Corporation - Papago Team

Specializing Multi-domain NMT via Penalizing Low Mutual Information (EMNLP 2022)

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

Advisory Committee Member

Sep 2023 - Feb 2024

SelectStar - LLM Dataset Construction

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Proceedings

- Jiyoung Lee, Minwoo Kim, Seungho Kim, Junghwan Kim, Seunghyun Won, Hwaran Lee, and Edward Choi. KorNAT: LLM Alignment Benchmark for Korean Social Values and Common Knowledge. In Findings in Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL) 2024
- Jiyoung Lee, Seungho Kim, Seunghyun Won, Joonseok Lee, Marzyeh Ghassemi, James Thorne, Jaeseok Choi,
 O-Kil Kwon, and Edward Choi. VisAlign: Dataset for Measuring the Degree of Alignment between AI and
 Humans in Visual Perception. In Proc. of Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2023 Datasets and
 Benchmarks
- Woncheol Shin, Gyubok Lee, **Jiyoung Lee**, Eunyi Lyou, Joonseok Lee, and Edward Choi. Translation-equivariant Image Quantizer for Bi-directional Image-Text Generation. In *Proc. of International Conference on Acoustics*, *Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP)* 2023, (Oral Presentation)
- **Jiyoung Lee**, Hantae Kim, Hyunchang Cho, Edward Choi, and Cheonbok Park. Specializing Multi-domain NMT via Penalizing Low Mutual Information. In *Proc. of Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP)* 2022

• Kyunghoon Hur*, **Jiyoung Lee***, Jungwoo Oh, Wesley Price, Young-Hak Kim, and Edward Choi. Unifying Heterogenous Electronic Health Records Systems via Text-Based Code Embedding. In *Proc. of Conference on Health, Inference, and Learning (CHIL)* 2022

Workshops, Preprints, and Domestic Conferences

- Radhika Dua, Jiyoung Lee, Joon-myung Kwon, and Edward Choi. Automatic Detection of Noisy Electrocardiogram Signals without Explicit Noise Labels. In *International Workshop on Pattern Recognition in Healthcare* Analytics (PRHA) 2022
- **Jiyoung Lee**, Wonjae Kim, Daehoon Gwak, and Edward Choi. Conditional Generation of Periodic Signals with Fourier-Based Decoder. In *Deep Generative Models and Downstream Applications Workshop at NeurIPS 2021*

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Program Language Packages	Python Pandas, Numpy, NLTK, Pytorch, HuggingFace, PyTorchLightning
Language	Korean (Native), English (Fluent)

EXPERIENCES

Teaching Assistant AI504: Programming for AI, KAIST, 2024 Fall

AI504: Programming for AI, KAIST, 2023 Fall

AI612: Machine Learning for Healthcare, KAIST, 2023 Spring

AI504: Programming for AI, KAIST, 2021 Fall

AI612: Machine Learning for Healthcare, KAIST, 2021 Spring

AI504: Programming for AI, KAIST, 2020 Fall

Academic Service ACCV 2022 Reviewer

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

NeurIPS 2023 Travel Award

Google Conference Scholarship 2022

National Science & Technology Scholarship (2018 - 2020)